TAHRIM UDDIN

SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer searching for a new opportunity. I have a passion for coding and have experience working on agile team under tight deadlines to ship quality web applications. Since discovering programming, I've worked diligently at improving my skills and learning new technologies everyday. I thrive in learning new concepts and adjusting to new environments. I have experience working both individually and in a group setting. I find great inspiration working closely with others and often push myself to new lengths when other people are relying on me.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS,

SQL/SQLite3/POSTgres

FRAMEWORKS: AcitveRecord, Ruby on Rails, JQuery, Sinatra,

AJAX, Bootstrap, API integration

TOOLS: Git, Heroku, Sublime, UNIX, VIM

TESTING: Rspec, Capybara, Factory Girl, CircleCi, Jasmine

PROJECTS

Juke

An interactive app for all music lovers. Juke is an app that allows you to crowd-source your playlist on Spotify.

Features:

Import playlists from Spotify

Create new Spotify playlists through our app

Invite guests to your hosted playlists, guests can then:

Up/down vote existing songs

Search for new songs to suggests, via the Spotify library View past invites

If they have a Spotify account, they can host their own lists Order your playlist according to vote count

NYCycle

NYCycle is an application that uses geolocation technology to allow you to locate the nearest recycling bin in NYC. Using data on bins from NYC Open Data, the user's location from their browser, and maps from the Google Maps API, we make it easy for people to do their part to reduce, reuse, and recycle. Features:

Find the closest recycling bin to your current location.

Find the closest recycling bin to any address.

View a map with directions to the recycling bin.

View a step by step directions to the recycling bin.

View a street view of the recycling bin.

CONTACT

■ utahrim@gmail.com

in utahrim
O utahrim

www.tahrimuddin.com

**** 561-319-5213

♥ West Palm Beach, FL

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp 2015

Full-Stack Web Developer Training Program

Florida Atlantic University Bachelor's Science 2014

EMPLOYMENT

Comfort Shoes

Boca Raton, FL

Salesman · May 2014 to Oct 2014

Helping clients select shoes that will make them happy in terms of overall fit, style and their budget.

Dealt with customer service and handled any returns or any other issues.

Negotiation to satisfy costumer in terms of price.

Organized stock room and handled any incoming packages. Managed store when the manager was not present.

Progressive Pharmacy

Wellington, FL

Pharmacist Assistant · Mar 2011 to Jul 2011

Stock and take inventory of prescription and over-the-counter medications.

Clean pharmacy equipment, help with the maintenance of equipment and supplies.

Manage the cash register.

VOLUNTEERING

Ahmadiyya Muslim Student Association · President Jan 2012 to Dec 2014

Founded the club at Florida Atlantic University.

Managed a team to organize charity events, soup kitchens and blood drives

Also, organized events for cleaning the beach and the highway with the community.